<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kishore Ganesh</title>
    <link>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kishore Ganesh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 01:40:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taking away control: The dumb programmer and the smart compiler</title>
      <link>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/post/programming_languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 01:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/post/programming_languages/</guid>
      <description>Good compilers prevent you from shooting yourself in the foot. Today, you have a wide assortment of programming languages to choose from, you can have your pick of paradigm. As a brief detour, the perspective of programmers comes full circle as they move from beginner to slightly experienced to intermediate.
The beginner is deathly afraid of the differences between programming languages. In the beginning, they stick to one language out of the fear of learning something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bootup</title>
      <link>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/post/bootup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:58:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/post/bootup/</guid>
      <description>A long, long time back, in a galaxy far far away, I was doing the same thing I&amp;rsquo;m doing right now. Booting up a blog. Genesis. Creation. My older blogs are many years behind me, and now a new journey begins.
I have witnessed a stark change in how I view blogging, or how I view writing in general over my 4 years of college. More on that in a later post, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to embark on this new journey, incorporating the many insights hidden away in some deep dark corner of my Google Keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kishore-ganesh.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi I&amp;rsquo;m Kishore Ganesh. I love everything about Computer Science, from nifty discrete math proofs to more concrete systems-domains like Operating System to visual domains like Computer Graphics. I love building projects, especially in domains I&amp;rsquo;m unfamiliar with.
One of my favorite things to do is to dive into a new topic and spend multiple weeks building up expertise on it.
My most notable projects are:
  Jack Toolchain: Wishing to know how computers work on a low level, I followed the NAND2Tetris book and built a computer from scratch in a hardware simulator, along with a two-phase compiler and assembler for the same computer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
